<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Pastor's Notebook</title>
    <description>Faith, politics, cookies
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 17:15:25 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 17:15:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Test Dog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been terribly neglectful of my Taco Tuesday duties, and also I needed a test post to see how my updated newsletter looked. I’ll tell you when I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2016-12-25/IMG_9441.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--share--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 10:28:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/29/test-dawg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/29/test-dawg.html</guid>
        
        <category>Taco</category>
        
        <category>Test</category>
        
        <category>Taco_Tuesday</category>
        
        <category>Good_dog</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Bridge the Reality Gap&amp;#58; An Answer in Hats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nancy LeTourneau delved into the mystery of the “&lt;a href=&quot;http://washingtonmonthly.com/2016/12/28/how-do-we-bridge-the-reality-gap/#.WGQrukbIUD0.twitter&quot;&gt;reality gap&lt;/a&gt;” over at the Washington Monthly blog earlier today. If you’re not familiar with that (the reality gap, not Washington Monthly), it’s the phenomenon of large segments of the population believing things that are demonstrably untrue, for example that unemployment has risen under Obama (it has not), or that more people are without health insurance (they are not). They call this a “gap” because—there is no gentle way to put this—it’s almost always Republicans who get the facts wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nancy says she’s open to suggestions, so here we go. Allow me to slip on my Liberal Hat first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GET RID OF FOX NEWS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work individually with the chronically misinformed to fill them in one step at a time. It seems like a thankless task, but trust me, it does something.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DID I MENTION GET RID OF FOX NEWS AND RUSH LIMBAUGH WHILE YOU’RE AT IT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a different perspective, &amp;lt;Pastor hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even liberal Christians have something to offer in insisting that there is an actual truth out there, a reality not of our own making. The gospel of John, for example, describes Jesus as “&lt;a href=&quot;http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=349980574&quot;&gt;full of grace and truth&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To insist on this truth, as Christians have done for thousands of years, does not require us to get entangled in debates about postmodernity or scientific-vs.-supernatural ways of knowing. The “truth” that John names has nothing to do with language games or dinosaur fossils. It is quite simply taking a stand in existence on the premise that the same restless, creative power of love that brought the universe into existence entered into flesh and blood in the man Jesus of Nazareth, and continues to work in those who choose to cooperate with it even today. Now &lt;em&gt;that’s&lt;/em&gt; a ballsy claim about reality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We can watch this truth unfold in the world around us, if we’re willing to listen for it, carefully, accurately, and without the defensive posture of wanting someone to tell us what “they” won’t. Christians have no business falling for lies, propoganda, fake news, or the temptation to give up on knowing what’s true and what’s not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Social Science hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, we also have to reckon with another truth, which is that people don’t choose their ideological affiliations because of the facts, but the other way around. They choose their truth based on which tribe they belong to. In a contest between believing that the first black president in particular and Democrats in general have accomplished great things for Americans or allowing the cozy assumptions of white supremacy to remain intact, well, which one do you think is going to win? That’s right: the option that tells the chooser they are a virtuous and responsible member of society, well-fit for and accepted by friends and neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Liberal Hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So you’re saying we’re screwed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Pastor hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We prefer to say “damned for all eternity.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Social Science hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m saying don’t hold your breath. It takes an extraordinary amount of work to break through the cognitive limits of group-think. It may be impossible to do it perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Pastor hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not a matter of absorbing and accepting facts, then, so much as repentance leading to the conversion of one’s very soul.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Social Science hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bingo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Liberal hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are so screwed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Pastor hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We prefer to say, “Come Lord Jesus! Come quickly!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;Social Science hat&amp;gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bingo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--share--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:39:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/28/bridging-the-reality-gap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/28/bridging-the-reality-gap.html</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>Christianity</category>
        
        <category>theology</category>
        
        <category>hats</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Santa Elf Does Not Care</title>
        <description>&lt;!--share--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/unhappyelf.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 12:51:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/25/santa-elf-doesnt-care.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/25/santa-elf-doesnt-care.html</guid>
        
        <category>Christmas</category>
        
        <category>Fussy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Christmas Special</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I trust that you have all had your fill of screaming kiddies opening presents, fighting with your in-laws, and “A Christmas Story.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a Christmas special for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So, then. Let us talk about Christmas, and what it means to you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, we have to back up a little to talk about Advent, though. That’s the four weeks leading up to Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It used to be the &lt;em&gt;six&lt;/em&gt; weeks before Christmas, and it was heavily penitential. Heavily. Heav-i-ly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(That’s why the traditional Advent color is purple, the same as in Lent, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Come to think of it, Advent is still penitential in a lot of ways. We hear all kinds of texts about judgment and apocalypse, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The O Antiphons, on which the familiar tune O Come O Come Emmanuel is based, also contain a subtle note of penitence.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They pray for God’s salvation from the world, which implies that we have mucked it up somehow. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/O_Antiphons&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then there’s Las Posadas, a Mexican re-enactment of the innkeeper turning away Mary and Joseph. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Las_Posadas&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Carolers go from house to house, asking to be let in. The residents refuse, they are chided for their inhospitality, there’s a song.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It all works out somehow. But tell me that’s not a relevant tradition today.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Advent, I think, is penitential even in the secular celebration of Christmas, even for people who aren’t religious!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I mean, think about this. How many iterations are there of “I’m Dreaming of a White Christmas”?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At the heart of that song is the nostalgia for simpler Christmases, for a lost simplicity, purity, and innocence.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(Also nostalgia for mayonnaise on Wonder bread. Good Lord, that song is white, and I’m not talking about the snow.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How many iterations of “A Christmas Carol” are there, in which a rich man repents of his sins and is reborn into new life?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There’s the battle every year over the commercialization of Christmas. (We regret not having deeper spiritual lives.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are complaints about the busyness of the season, the burden it places on moms. (Are we wasting our lives on non-essentials?)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We talk about people who mourn instead of rejoice at Christmas. (We acknowledge our tattered social relationships.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We talk about these people or those who are overlooked in a supposed season of generosity. (We confess our greed and hard-heartedness.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yes, there’s even the stupid War on Christmas. (Some of us are afraid we don’t know why we’re celebrating.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(Others don’t find superficial piety in a Kohl’s checkout line to be spiritually persuasive.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(Jesus would have had no frigging idea what you were talking about if you said “Merry Christmas” to him.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(There’s no solid evidence Christmas was even widely celebrated until the mid-5th century.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What it all comes down to is that we sense a disconnect between a hoped-for perfection and the reality of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We sense that disconnect, and we start to get the idea that maybe we’re responsible for it somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take all the bitching that goes on between Thanksgiving and Christmas as ritual expressions of that fear and penitence…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;…and you’ll never see December the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And here we come to the Christmas blessing. The perfect &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; come into the world today, or so Christians say, in the form of a baby.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The Word became flesh and lived among us, and we have seen his glory, the glory as of a father’s only son, full of grace and truth.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God risks contingency to bring Jesus the savior into the world. He could have died. Mary could have died.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God risks weakness to come into the world. A baby is indeed helpless, dependent on others.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some people are eager to rush past this weakness to get to the Christ who died on the cross, a warrior against Satan.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;That’s inappropriate. Stick with the baby. The infant Jesus does not point to the cross, because the cross did not have to be inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Overlooked in these familiar ways of looking at the birth of Jesus is another, the very content of John’s “grace and truth.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus—God’s perfection born of the woman Mary—comes into the world in a web of social relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He’s not just born into those relationships; he blesses them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s almost impossible to raise an infant without help. True today, true in Mary and Joseph’s day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus’ advent blesses the man Joseph who stuck around to love and care for a child not his own.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It blesses Mary, who was brave enough to say yes to God’s love made manifest in this baby boy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Through them, it blesses all of us who love and care for one another, children or adults alike.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As anyone who’s ever raised a kid knows, there’s no such thing as a perfect parent. You can only aspire to be good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There’s ups and downs, difficult parts and surprising moments of smooth sailing and grace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But if you’re bonded to that kid, and you try to do right by them, that’s good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Paul’s letter to Titus says, “when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us…”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“…not because of any [of our] works of righteousness that we had done, but according to his mercy.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God loves us like an infant loves its mother, and seeks the same in return.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We don’t have to be perfect, we don’t have to be without sin, we just have to let ourselves be loved by God.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So this Christmas, instead of worrying about the perfect dinner, or if the gifts or the tree are just right…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember this: God was born today a tiny infant to a young woman in an area usually reserved for the animals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And if we can love one another like Joseph and Mary loved that baby, that’s all the perfect we need to be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/25/christmas-special.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/25/christmas-special.html</guid>
        
        <category>Christmas</category>
        
        <category>Sermon</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A little Christmas present for you</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In just less than a month, a man with a series of negative qualities almost too long to list will take over the White House from the first black president. He is a racist, he is a xenophobe, a bigot, a misogynist. He is a reckless businessman who has run bankrupt multiple times, cheated everyone he could, and perjured himself again and again in lawsuits. He is by his own admission a serial abuser of women and a general creep. There is much more beside this. None of this is an insult, by the way, only fair and demonstrable characterization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next year, I am planning a series of columns on how the church can respond to this new situation. More on that later. Right now, let us say the series needs to focus less on the man and more on the social currents he provokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s first of all because those currents are more important than the man himself. If 2016 revealed anything about our nation, it’s that the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Politics-Resentment-Consciousness-Wisconsin-American/dp/022634911X&quot;&gt;politics of resentment&lt;/a&gt;” are alive and well. Those, and not the man, are what the church is called to face down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, as François Truffaut said, “Every film about war ends up being pro-war,” and “to show something is to ennoble it.” Or in this case, to name it is to empower it. The president-elect shows all the signs of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Politics-Resentment-Consciousness-Wisconsin-American/dp/022634911X&quot;&gt;raging narcissistic behavior&lt;/a&gt;]. Focusing on him only repeats his frame of reference: it’s all about him. And making it all about him gives him both &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; strength to continue his inappropriate behavior, and the &lt;em&gt;political&lt;/em&gt; means to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not obliged to dump gasoline on that particular fire. From this point on, I will spend as little time as possible talking about the president-elect. America is not about him, and certainly not the Christian faith. Nor will I use his name here, except to describe the movement he inspires: trumpismo. Dude slaps his trademark on everything else he can reach, but he doesn’t get to brand this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 05:50:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/24/a-little-christmas-present.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/24/a-little-christmas-present.html</guid>
        
        <category>-That</category>
        
        <category>man</category>
        
        <category>-Disobedience</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Didymus</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A little something I wrote the other day on St. Thomas, on what used to be his day (December 21).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/didymus/embed?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/didymus.js?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/didymus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;Didymus&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 23:17:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/22/didymus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/22/didymus.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things To Do While That Man Is President</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just after the election, while I and all my liberal friends were down in the dumps, I got tired of just waiting for the worst to happen. So I put together a little (ha, ha) list of things we could do instead. At my friend Marcy’s request, I’m pulling it together for spreading around purposes. You’re welcome to send suggestions/additions if you like.  You should also read &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1DzOz3Y6D8g_MNXHNMJYAz1b41_cn535aU5UsN7Lj8X8/preview&quot;&gt;Indivisible: A Practical Guide for Resisting the Trump Agenda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see. I bet I can come up with 20 things you can do to make life better under Trump, instead of rolling over and playing dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show kindness, especially to people you wouldn’t normally. Notice the homeless; reach out to a conservative relative.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Help someone register to vote. Start now, while there’s plenty of time to negotiate the maze.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Write a letter to Hillary Clinton, thanking her for her effort. Same with Obama. Write to Joe Biden and tell him he’s been a bitchin’ VP.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Celebrate relationships of your gay &amp;amp; lesbian friends. If you know someone who is transsexual, tell them you accept them for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tell everyone you know that you won’t stand for hateful attacks. I’ve already told my congregation, and will my classes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If there is some act of hate in your area, let everyone know you condemn it in the strongest possible terms. Say it loudly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Visit a mosque near you. Pray with the community. Tell them you are proud to be associated with them. Mean it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Eat at a Mexican restaurant and leave a big tip. Write “Fuck Donald Trump” on the receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Celebrate Cinco de Mayo or attend a seder dinner, if you’re invited.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get into woke and socially-aware music, especially in all-white areas. I like to blast Norteño and Mexican hip-hop in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Work in a soup kitchen or volunteer at a food pantry. It needs to be done anyway, even more now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A couple of hard one: if you don’t like mega-corporate banks, join a credit union. Help start one for underserved neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Foster a child. Welcome that little stranger into your home and love them, deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re part of a church, work to make sure it’s open and affirming, welcoming to all people. Make sure that shows up in worship.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Teach your children to reject hate. Encourage them to be leaders in standing up to bullies and bigots.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take your daughter to a self-defense class. Teach her how to be safe. Teach your son to respect women &amp;amp; prevent others from harming them&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you live in a mostly white area, especially if rural, talk about your experiences outside the neighborhood. Highlight diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If somebody tells a racist or sexist joke in your presence, tell them you don’t like humor that hurts people. When they say “What’s the matter, can’t you take a joke?” don’t get angry. Tell them how sad and hurt it makes you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you want to be a little more partisan/political, when somebody mentions how the little guy is getting screwed by big companies, point out how Trump is in bed with those same companies. Wouldn’t it be nice if someone would actually help someone like you?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Along the lines of 18 ☝︎, if somebody says, “Thank God we don’t have be politically correct anymore!” Tell them you prefer not to be hurtful with your language.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t be ashamed to read books by minority/gay authors. Same with films, TV, music. You like Blackish or Modern Family? Let people know!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More hard ones: shelter an undocumented immigrant. Help resettle a refugee. Help a young woman get an abortion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep the pressure on for Black Lives Matter. Post bail for someone arrested in a protest. Buy them a gas mask, if need be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take a chance on employing somebody who’s served time in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to giving money to &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.ppaction.org/Donate/Defend‎&quot;&gt;Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/donate/join-renew-give&quot;&gt;ACLU&lt;/a&gt;, among others, support a blogger or independent journalist. Recommended: &lt;a href=&quot;http://digbysblog.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Digby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://atrios.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Atrios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarahposner.com/&quot;&gt;Sarah Posner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://oliverwillis.com/about/&quot;&gt;Oliver Willis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emptywheel.net/about/&quot;&gt;emptywheel&lt;/a&gt; and oh so many more, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://religiondispatches.org&quot;&gt;Religion Dispatches&lt;/a&gt;, or, erm, &lt;a href=&quot;http://apastorsnotebook.com/support.html&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re the praying sort, pray for yourself, and for forgiveness for your political opponents. Shut up. Do it anyway. Go to church. Participate in and support the community. Civil society is &lt;em&gt;important&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Volunteer on a reservation. Remind yourself of what your priorities should be, and who deserves your support.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make a friend outside your usual social circle. Stick with them even if things get tough, politically.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finishing up: if you’d like to hang out with Muslims, see if you can wangle an invitation to an iftar dinner. They are &lt;em&gt;amazing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If fostering a child isn’t your thing, mentor a kid, or volunteer in a class. Love the little bastards.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In any case, you get the idea. The worst victory the alt-right could win would be to make the US a meaner, more divided place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Refuse to allow yourself to be shut off from others, foster connections wherever you can, celebrate diversity. Remain human, publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At the same time, if you need alternatives to the system, build them, or fund them, quietly. Fuck the man.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ll bet you all could come up with 50 more. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Oh, but one more: Never tweet. Don’t make lists, either.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 21:19:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/19/things-to-do-while-that-man-is-president.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/19/things-to-do-while-that-man-is-president.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This is just an irresponsible amount of sermon, tbh</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/jesus-mary-but-mostly-joseph/embed?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/jesus-mary-but-mostly-joseph.js?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/jesus-mary-but-mostly-joseph&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;Jesus, Mary, but mostly, Joseph&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, there’s more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/how-in-the-heck-do-i-have-more-to-say-about-mary-a/embed?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/how-in-the-heck-do-i-have-more-to-say-about-mary-a.js?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/how-in-the-heck-do-i-have-more-to-say-about-mary-a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;How in the heck do I have more to say about Mary and Joseph?&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 19:21:28 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/18/an-irresponsible-amount-of-sermon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/18/an-irresponsible-amount-of-sermon.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hope somebody filled your stockings with glee</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/hope-somebody-filled-your-stockings-with-glee/embed?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/hope-somebody-filled-your-stockings-with-glee.js?border=false&amp;amp;template=slideshow&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/hope-somebody-filled-your-stockings-with-glee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;Hope somebody filled your stockings with glee&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As always, &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/pastordan/hope-somebody-filled-your-stockings-with-glee&quot;&gt;here’s a link&lt;/a&gt; in case the Storify embed doesn’t work.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 20:31:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/06/hope-somebody-filled-your-stockings-with-glee.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/06/hope-somebody-filled-your-stockings-with-glee.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>People, Get Ready</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Disregard the image below. You’ll know it when you see it. Disregard it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sermon about preparing for Christ’s return. You can also read it &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/pastordan/people-get-ready&quot;&gt;on Storify&lt;/a&gt; if the embed below doesn’t work or simply annoys you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregard the image!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/people-get-ready/embed?template=slideshow&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/people-get-ready.js?template=slideshow&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;//storify.com/pastordan/people-get-ready&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the story &quot;People, get ready&quot; on Storify&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/04/people-get-ready.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/04/people-get-ready.html</guid>
        
        <category>sermon</category>
        
        <category>isaiah</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
